Guide to the Paul Buhle Papers TAM.171
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV, Writings, 1964-1992
  - Unpublished Writings, 1964-1992
    Materials in this subseries consist of unpublished writings by Buhle. Materials include papers and essays written by Buhle as an undergraduate and graduate student, including his Master's and PhD theses. Also included are notebooks, drafts of essays, and lecture notes about the activities of Radical America, its transformation from a graduate student journal associated with Students for a Democratic Society to an established political publication, and its efforts to reformulate its political orientation as the publication developed. Other materials in this subseries include syllabi and notes for two classes at the Cambridge Goddard Graduate School, as well as notes exchanged with journalist Dave Wagner concerning popular culture studies and labor history in Rhode Island.
    Subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Undergraduate writings: Outlines, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Undergraduate writings: Papers, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Undergraduate writings: Papers, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Undergraduate writings: Thesis draft, circa 1966 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Graduate school writings: Book reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Graduate school writings: Exams, circa 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Graduate school writings: Lecture notes, circa 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Graduate school writings: Papers: General, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Graduate school writings: Papers: "Realignment in the 1930s", 1967 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Gradute school writings: "Louis C. Fraina, 1894-1953" [Master's thesis] (1 of 2 folders), 1968 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Gradute school writings: "Louis C. Fraina, 1894-1953" [Master's thesis] (2 of 2 folders), 1968 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Editorials and op-eds, 1964-1977 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Students for a Democratic Society, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Essay: "American Liberalism: Some Questions", Jun 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Radical America notebooks, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Radical America notebooks, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Essay: "Resynthesis", 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Essays on Melvyn Dubofsky, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Essay: "Marcuse and the New Left", 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Criticism of Paul Buhle, circa 1968-1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Socialist Scholars Conference, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Autobiographical writings, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Essay: "Marxism in the United States: 39 Propositions", Nov 1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Unfinished popular culture project for Institute of Policy Studies, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Radical America Boston writings, Aug 1971-Jun 1973 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Essay on American Marxism, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Essay on readings for class on American radicalism, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Reflections on Radical America, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) history conference, Apr 15, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Essay on Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), 1972, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Essay: "Debsian Socialism: An Overview", 1973 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Essay on Marxism and popular culture for Popular Culture Conference in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Speech draft: "Factory and Society", Dec 12, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - "Man and Woman in America" social history project, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Essay on Radical America, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Essay on Critical Interruptions: New Left Perspectives on Herbert Marcuse, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Essay on Harvey Swados and Stan Weir, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Essay on New Left: May Day Manifesto, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Essay on state capitalism, circa 1975 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Essay on television, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Essay on Third Party Footprints, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Essays on James Weinstein (1 of 2 folders), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Essays on James Weinstein (2 of 2 folders), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Essay on The Young Lukacs by Andrew Arato and Paul Breines, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Speech drafts: Marxism, circa 1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Speech drafts: Socialist literature, circa 1975 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Essay: "Studies in Radical History, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Speech drafts: MARHO forum, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Essay on Herbert Gutman, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Essay on popular front culture, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Essay: "Finns in America", circa 1976 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Essay: "Historians, Culture, and the Lower Classes", circa 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Essay ideas research memos, Aug 1976 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Essay: "Red, White, Blue, Revolutionary", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Rhode Island Labor History Forum, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - The Oral History of the American Left, after 1976 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Essay: "Gridironing on Bluto", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Television documentary on social movements in New York [Never made], 1977 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Essay on R. Crumb, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Essay: "Notes on the New Comics", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Essay: "Pullman: Focus on Social Confrontation", Mar 1977 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Essay: "Socialist Sentimentalism", Sep 1977 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Interview questions, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Essay: "American Labor's Pioneer Authors", 1980 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Essay on Italian Americans, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Essay on Lawrence Ferlinghetti, circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Essay: "Left Culture in the United States", circa 1980 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Essay: "Return of the Comix", 1980 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Essay: "America Looks Forward to Election Day", Sep 1980 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Essay: "Worker Culture/Radical Cultures", Sep 1980 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Essay: "Peace Culture/Popular Culture/Left Culture", 1980-1982 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Essay: "Consumers Consumed", circa 1982 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Essay: "Radicalism Renewed?", circa 1982 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Essay: "Humor in the American Left: Old Immigrant Meets New Upon the Plain of Meloncholy Fantastia", circa 1983 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Essay: "In Sam Liptzin's Library", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Essay: "Old Wounds", circa 1983 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Lecture on television, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Unpublished letter on Socialist Action, Apr 12, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Essay: "The Vanished Yiddish Soul of C and W", 1984 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Essay: "Maurice Kish, Nightside Dreamer", 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Essay: "Anarchism and American Labor", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Essay on science fiction, circa 1985 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Essay: "The Left, the National Question, and Immigrant Radicalism in the United States", 1985 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Essay: "Marxism in the United States", 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Essay: "Culture and Revolutionary Struggle: Legacy and Prospects", circa 1986 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Essay: "Liberation Theology and Marxism: A Mediation", circa 1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Essay: "DSA: A Cultural Program", circa 1987 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Essay on the Immigrant Left, circa 1987 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Essay: "The Radical Tradition", 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Lectures on Yiddish, circa 1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Incomplete drafts and outlines, 1970-1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Essay on CLR James [incomplete], undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Essay on television detectives, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Lecture on New Unionism, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Essay: "Moshe Nadir and the Soul of Yiddish Humor", undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Essay: "Overview of 1877-1890", undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Published Writings, 1966-1991
    Materials in this subseries consist of Buhle's published writings, including articles and book reviews in scholarly journals and leftwing political newspapers on topics such as the history of American radicalism, radicalism in popular culture, and recent developments in labor history scholarship.
    - Journal articles, 1966-1967; cuid33671 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Journal articles, May 1975-May 1990 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper articles, Sep 1966-Sep 1988 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper articles, Feb 1988-May 1990; cuid33672 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Book reviews, Oct 1968-May 1985 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Book reviews, 1986-1991 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Reviews of Paul Buhle's books, 1981-1990; cuid33673 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Rhode Island DSA newsletter, 1986; cuid33674 (Box 15, Folder 19)